{"name": "\u65e7OG1  1MC", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. Kaya ran  miles on Monday and miles on Tuesday. What was the total distance, in miles, Kayaran during those 2 days?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " ", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. 3x3 \u00b7 2x2y \u00b7 4x2y is equivalent to\uff1a", "choices": {"A": "9x7y2", "B": "9x12y2", "C": "24x7y2", "D": "24x12y", "E": "24x12y2"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Mr. Dietz is a teacher whose salary is $22,570 for this school year, which has 185 days. In Mr. Dietz\u2019s school district, substitute teachers are paid $80 per day. If Mr. Dietz takes a day off without pay and a substitute teacher is paid to teach Mr. Dietz\u2019s classes, how much less does the school district pay in salary by paying a substitute teacher instead of paying Mr. Dietz for that day ?", "choices": {"A": "$ 42", "B": "$ 80", "C": "$ 97", "D": "$ 105", "E": "$ 122"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. So far, a student has earned the following scores on four 100-point tests this grading period: 65, 73, 81, and 82. What score must the student earn on the fifth and last 100-point test of the grading period to earn an average test grade of 80 for the 5 tests ?", "choices": {"A": "75", "B": "76", "C": "78", "D": "99", "E": "The student cannot earn an average of 80."}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. The oxygen saturation level of a river is found by dividing the amount of dissolved oxygen the river water currently has per liter by the dissolved oxygen capacity per liter of the water and then converting to a percent. If the river currently has 7.3 milligrams of dissolved oxygen per liter of water and the dissolved oxygen capacity is 9.8 milligrams per liter, what is the oxygen saturation level, to the nearest percent ?", "choices": {"A": "34%", "B": "70%", "C": "73%", "D": "74%", "E": "98%"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. A rectangular lot that measures 150 ft by 200 ft is completely fenced. What is the approximate length, in feet, of the fence?", "choices": {"A": "300", "B": "350", "C": "400", "D": "700", "E": "1,400"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. The expression a[b + (c - d)] is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "ab + ac - ad", "B": "ab + ac + ad", "C": "ab + ac - d", "D": "ab + c + d", "E": "ab + c - d"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. If 4x + 3 = 9x - 4, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. What 2 numbers should be placed in the blanks below so that the difference between consecutive numbers is the same?                  17, ____ , ____ , 41", "choices": {"A": "23, 29", "B": "24, 34", "C": "25, 33", "D": "26, 35", "E": "27, 31"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. If x is a real number such that x3 = 64, then  = ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "10", "C": "18", "D": "20", "E": "47"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. A formula for the volume V of a sphere with radius r is . If the radius of a spherical rubber ball is inches, what is its volume to the nearest cubic inch?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "7", "C": "8", "D": "16", "E": "65"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. If a marble is randomly chosen from a bag that contains exactly 8 red marbles, 6 blue marbles, and 6 white marbles, what is the probability that the marble will NOT be white?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. The number of students participating in fall sports at a certain high school can be shown by the following matrix.        Tennis      Soccer   Cross-Country   Football         [  40            60                80                    80   ]The athletic director estimates the ratio of the number of sports awards that will be earned to the number of students participating with the following matrix.              Given these matrices, what is the athletic director\u2019s estimate for the number of sports awards that will be earned for these fall sports?", "choices": {"A": "80", "B": "88", "C": "91", "D": "92", "E": "99"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. Use the following information to answer questions 14-15.The following chart shows the current enrollment in all the mathematics classes offered by Eastside High School.                       14.\tWhat is the average number of students enrolled per section in Algebra I ?", "choices": {"A": "24", "B": "25", "C": "26", "D": "27", "E": "29"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Use the following information to answer questions 14-15.The following chart shows the current enrollment in all the mathematics classes offered by Eastside High School.        15.The school owns 2 classroom sets of 30 calculators each, which students are required to have during their mathematics class. There are 2 calculators from one set and 6 calculators from the other set that are not available for use by the students because these calculators are being repaired. For which of the following class periods, if any, are there NOT enough calculators available for each student to use a school-owned calculator without having to share?", "choices": {"A": "Period 2 only", "B": "Period 3 only", "C": "Period 4 only", "D": "Periods 3 and 4 only", "E": "There are enough calculators for each class period."}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. What expression must the center cell of the table below contain so that the sums of each row, each column, and each diagonal are equivalent?", "choices": {"A": "6x", "B": "4x", "C": "2x", "D": "-2x", "E": "-4x"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. Point A is to be graphed in a quadrant, not on an axis, of the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below.If the x-coordinate and the y-coordinate of point A are to have opposite signs, then point A must be located in:", "choices": {"A": "Quadrant II only.", "B": "Quadrant IV only.", "C": "Quadrant I or III only.", "D": "Quadrant I or IV only.", "E": "Quadrant II or IV only."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. Kareem has 4 sweaters, 6 shirts, and 3 pairs of slacks. How many distinct outfits, each consisting of a sweater, a shirt, and a pair of slacks, can Kareem select?", "choices": {"A": "13", "B": "36", "C": "42", "D": "72", "E": "216"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. At a refinery, 100,000 tons of sand are required to produce each 60,000 barrels of a tarry material. How many tons of sand are required to produce 3,000\tbarrels of this tarry material?", "choices": {"A": "5,000", "B": "18,000", "C": "20,000", "D": "40,000", "E": "50,000"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. If a rectangle measures 54 meters by 72 meters, what is the length, in meters, of the diagonal of the rectangle?", "choices": {"A": "48", "B": "63", "C": "90", "D": "126", "E": "252"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. For all positive integers x, y, and z, which of the following expressions is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. What is the slope-intercept form of 8x - y - 6 = 0 ?", "choices": {"A": "y = -8x - 6", "B": "y = -8x + 6", "C": "y = 8x - 6", "D": "y = 8x + 6", "E": "y = 6x - 8"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Which of the following is a solution to the equation x2 - 36x = 0 ?", "choices": {"A": "72", "B": "36", "C": "18", "D": "6", "E": "-6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. For right triangle \u25b3RST shown below, what is tan R ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. A chord 24 inches long is 5 inches from the center of a circle, as shown below. What is the radius of the circle, to the nearest tenth of an inch?", "choices": {"A": "29.0", "B": "24.5", "C": "16.9", "D": "13.0", "E": "10.9"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. The length L, in meters, of a spring is given by the equation L=F + 0.03 , where F is the applied force in newtons. What force, in newtons, must be applied for the spring\u2019s length to be 0.18 meters?", "choices": {"A": "0.13", "B": "0.15", "C": "0.225", "D": "0.255", "E": "0.27"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. After a snowstorm, city workers removed an estimated 10,000 cubic yards of snow from the downtown area. If this snow were spread in an even layer over the entire rectangular football field shown below, about how many yards deep would the layer of snow be?", "choices": {"A": "Less than 1", "B": "Between 1 and 2", "C": "Between 2 and 3", "D": "Between 3 and 4", "E": "More than 4"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. The hypotenuse of the right triangle \u25b3PQR shown below is 16 feet long. The sine of \u2220P   is . About how many feet long is QR ?", "choices": {"A": "8.0", "B": "9.6", "C": "12.4", "D": "14.3", "E": "15.4"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. The graph below shows the number of cars assembled last year in 4 cities, to the nearest 5,000 cars. According to the graph, what fraction of the cars assembled in all 4 cities were assembled in Coupeville?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Points B and C lie on AD as shown below. The length of AD is 30 units; AC is 16 units long; and BD is 20 units long. How many units long, if it can be determined, is BC ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "6", "C": "10", "D": "14", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. What is the x-coordinate of the point in the standard(x, y) coordinate plane at which the 2 lines y = 2x + 6  and y = 3x + 4 intersect ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "4", "D": "6", "E": "10"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. For all pairs of real numbers M and V where M = 3V + 6,\tV = \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "3M - 6", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Parallelogram ABCD, with dimensions in inches, is shown in the diagram below. What is the area of the parallelogram, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "18", "B": "36", "C": "39", "D": "45", "E": "72"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. If a = b + 2, then (b - a)4 = ?", "choices": {"A": "-16", "B": "-8", "C": "1", "D": "8", "E": "16"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. A park has the shape and dimensions in blocks given below. A water fountain is located halfway between point B and point D. Which of the following is the location of the water fountain from point A ?(Note: The park\u2019s borders run east-west or north-south.)", "choices": {"A": "blocks east and 6 blocks north", "B": "5 blocks east and  blocks north", "C": "5 blocks east and 6 blocks north", "D": "blocks east and  blocks north", "E": "9 blocks east and  blocks north"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. The larger of two numbers exceeds twice the smaller number by 8. The sum of twice the larger and 3 times the smaller number is 65. If x is the smaller number, which equation below determines the correct value of x ?", "choices": {"A": "3(2x + 8) + 2x = 65", "B": "3(2x - 8) + 2x = 65", "C": "(4x + 8) + 3x = 65", "D": "2(2x +8) + 3x = 65", "E": "2(2x - 8) + 3x = 65"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Members of the fire department lean a 30-foot ladder against a building. The side of the building is perpendicular to the level ground so that the base of the ladder is 10 feet away from the base of the building. To the nearest foot, how far up the building does the ladder reach?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "20", "C": "28", "D": "31", "E": "40"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. A square is circumscribed about a circle of 7-foot radius, as shown below. What is the area of the square, in square feet?", "choices": {"A": "49", "B": "56", "C": "98", "D": "49\u03c0", "E": "196"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. The ratio of the side lengths for a triangle is exactly 12:14:15. In a second triangle similar to the first, the shortest side is 8 inches long. To the nearest tenth of an inch, what is the length of the longest side of the second triangle?", "choices": {"A": "11.0", "B": "10.0", "C": "9.3", "D": "6.4", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. In the figure below, ABCD is a trapezoid, E lies on , and angle measures are as marked. What is the measure of \u2220BDC ?", "choices": {"A": "15\u00b0", "B": "25\u00b0", "C": "30\u00b0", "D": "35\u00b0", "E": "45\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. In the figure shown below, each pair of intersecting line segments meets at a right angle, and all the lengths given are in inches. What is the perimeter, in inches, of the figure?", "choices": {"A": "40", "B": "52", "C": "56", "D": "66", "E": "80"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Of the 804 graduating seniors in a certain high school, approximately are going to college and approximatelyof those going to college are going to a state university. Which of the following is the closest estimate for how many of the graduating seniors are going to a state university?", "choices": {"A": "80", "B": "90", "C": "160", "D": "200", "E": "320"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. If x and y and  are positive integers such that the greatest common factor of x2y2  and xy3 is 45, then which of the following could y equal?", "choices": {"A": "45", "B": "15", "C": "9", "D": "5", "E": "3"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. If 115% of a number is 460, what is 75% of the number?", "choices": {"A": "280", "B": "300", "C": "320", "D": "345", "E": "400"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. What is the distance in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane between the points (1, 0) and (0, 5) ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "6", "C": "16", "D": "36", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. The ratio of the radii of two circles is 4:9. What is the ratio of their circumferences?", "choices": {"A": "2:3", "B": "4:9", "C": "16:81", "D": "4:8\u03c0", "E": "9:18\u03c0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. A circle in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane is tangent to the x-axis at 5 and tangent to the y-axis at 5. Which of the following is an equation of the circle?", "choices": {"A": "x2 + y2 = 5 ", "B": "x2 + y2 = 25", "C": "(x - 5)2 + (y - 5)2 = 5", "D": "(x - 5)2 + (y - 5)2 = 25", "E": "(x + 5)2 + (y + 5)2 = 25"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. In the complex numbers, where ,  = ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Which of the following statements describes the total number of dots in the first  n rows of the triangular arrangement illustrated below?                        ", "choices": {"A": "This total is always equal to 25 regardless of the number of rows.", "B": "This total is equal to twice the number of rows.", "C": "This total is equal to 5 times the number of rows.", "D": "This total is equal to the square of the number of rows.", "E": "There is no consistent relationship between this total and the number of rows."}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. After polling a class of 20 music students by a show of hands, you find that 8 students play the guitar and 9 students play the piano. Given that information, what is the minimum number of students in this music class who play both the guitar and the piano?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "8", "D": "9", "E": "17"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Which of the following is the set of all real numbers x such that x + 3 &gt; x + 5 ?", "choices": {"A": "The empty set", "B": "The set containing all real numbers", "C": "The set containing all negative real numbers", "D": "The set containing all nonnegative real numbers", "E": "The set containing only zero"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Pentagons have 5 diagonals, as illustrated below.How many diagonals does the octagon below have?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "16", "C": "20", "D": "30", "E": "40"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. Douglas wants to draw a circle graph showing the favorite colors of his friends. When he polled his friends asking each their favorite color, 25% of his friends said red; 30% of his friends said blue; 20% of his friends said green; 10% of his friends said purple; and the remaining friends said colors other than red, blue, green, and purple. The colors other than red, blue, green, and purple will be grouped together in an Other sector. What will be the degree measure of the Other sector?", "choices": {"A": "108\u00b0", "B": "54\u00b0", "C": "27\u00b0", "D": "15\u00b0", "E": "10\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. If sin \ud835\udec9 = -, and \uff0cthen tan \ud835\udec9 = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. Which of the following systems of inequalities is represented by the shaded region of the graph below?", "choices": {"A": "y \u2264 -2x and x \u2265 3", "B": "y \u2264 -2x or x \u2265 3", "C": "y \u2265 -2x and x \u2265 3", "D": "y \u2265 -2x or x \u2265 3", "E": "y \u2265 -2x and x \u2264 3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. If f(x) = x2 - 2, then f(x + h) = ? ", "choices": {"A": "x2 + h2", "B": "x2 - 2 + h", "C": "x2 + h2 - 2", "D": "x2 + 2xh + h2", "E": "x2 + 2xh + h2 - 2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. Which of the following is the graph, in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, of ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. A triangle, \u25b3ABC, is reflected across the x-axis to have the image \u25b3A'B'C' in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane; thus, A reflects to A'. The coordinates of point A are (c, d). What are the coordinates of point A' ?", "choices": {"A": "( c, -d)", "B": "(-c,  d)", "C": "(-c, -d)", "D": "( d,  c)", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. If x = 2t - 9  and y = 5 - t, which of the following expresses y in terms of x?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "y = 14 - 2x", "D": "y = 5 - x", "E": "y = 1 - x"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. What isgiven that and that sin(\u03b1 - \u03b2) = (sin \u03b1)(cos \u03b2) - (cos \u03b1)(sin \u03b2) ?(Note: You may use the following table of values.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}]}